Guide to the W. Y. (Walter Yeeling) Evans-Wentz Papers, 1894-1961
Department of Special Collections
- Miscellaneous, including letters, notes and printed material. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Small green notebook with Wentz' notes on Shakti & Shakta
    (Sir John Woodroffe... 1918)
  - 1918, Dec 27,Anton Niedermeier [?] to Wentz, ALS., 4 pp
  - Oxford University Press bill, with enclosed calling cards.
  - Receipt for money order payable to J. H. Fussell.
  - n.b. - the old cloth on this ms., adorned with the sun in centre and four crescent moons, symbols of Buddhism, is the covering which was on the ms. when it came from the monastery. stamp for the disabled Ceylon Men's fund.
- Sikh Holy Bible, First Sections, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- 4 Descriptions of art work and scrolls, n.d.[Art and scrolls not available.] Includes translation of Chinese Imperial poem copied by Tsao Wen Chih. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Tirukalukundrum Patchi Dharisana Chart. Viadras: Counian Press, 1918.15th ed., 4,000 copies. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Ashtavakra Gita, Trans. by Hari Prasad Shastri (Box 9)
- Baba, Meher, Life at Its Best, foreward by E-W
- Berner, H. Charles, A Manual for Guiding a Person Through the After Death Experience
- Bhagwat, Professor, N.K., The Dhammapda
- Blavatsky, H.P., Studies in Occultism, No. VI
- Buddhism and Science, Buddhist Publication Society
- Coyas, Arturo, Appelton's New Spanish-English and English-Spanish Dictionary
- Collier, John, Indians of the Americas
- Cotton-Clad Mila: The Tibetan Poet-Saint's Life in Pictures, Columbia Univ. Press
- English Club of Stanford University, (framed certificate)
- Estele, Dr., Urinary Disorders of Prostatic Origin
- Five Hymns to Sri Arunachala, Niranjananda Swamy Publisher, (2copies)
- First Steps in Occultism, Theosophical Publishing Society
- Good and Evil, Theosophical University Press, Point Long, California
- Hood, Tom, The Rhymester
- James, Laura DeWitt, The Word Went Forth
- Jesus College of Oxford: List of Old Members
- Krishnamurti, J. At The Feet of the Master
- La Lengua Aymara, Hermana Mayor de la Quichua Mendoza 1945(J. P. Harrington)
- Lewis, L.A. Ancient Secret Wisdom
- Luce E Ombra, Linotipia Veronese Ghidini E. Fiorini-Verona article by E-W
- Moss, Charles M., A First Greek Reader
- Nimalasuria, Dr. A., ed, Buddha The Healer
- Osborne, Arthur Ramana Arunachala
- Pictures (3) one of Seventeenth International Congress of Orientalists, Oxford, 1928
- Ramanasramaim, Sri, Advanta Badha Deepika
- Ramsey, M. Montrose, A Spanish Grammer
- Ramsey, M. Montrose, Modern Spanish
- Rancha Sila: The Five Precepts, Theosophical Publishing House
- Shelton, Herbert M. The Spirit of Right Living
- Sinha, J. Wettha, The Four Retentions of Memory
- Sinnett, A.P. The Occult World
- Suggestions to Homesteaders and Persons Desiring to Make Homestead Entries, Washington Gov. Printing Office
- The American Philosophy Series: Oriental Philosophies, Russell F. Moore Co. Publishers foreward by E-W
- The Canadian Theosophist, Vol XXIII, No. 6., Hamilton, August 1942see p1
- The Canadian Theosophist, Vol XXIII, No. 10, Hamilton, December 1942,see p1
- The Canadian Theosophist, Vol XXIII, No. 11, Hamilton, January 1943see p1
- The Canadian Theosophist, Vol XXIV, No. 1, Hamilton, March 15, 1943see p11
- The Canadian Theosophist, Vol XXIV, No. 7, Hamilton, September 1943see p202
- The Canadian Theosophist, Vol XXVII, No. 1, Hamilton, March 1946,article by E-W p6
- The High History of the Holy Grail, translated by Sebastian Evans Vol. two
- The Jewel of Trancendental Wisdom (The Diamond Sutra) A.F. Price Trans. foreward by E-
- The Junior Theosophist, Vol. VIII, No 9, May 1938,article by E-W p159
- The Last Word: The Sutra of the Teachings Left by the Buddha, Pub. by Koyata Yamamota
- The Listener Vol XLIII, No. 1096, January 1950
- The Maha Bodhi, Vol. 61, Nos. 5-6, May-Junearticle by E-W, p61
- The Maha Bodhi, Vol. 49, No. 10 October
- The Maha Bodhi, Vol. 58, Nos. 4-5, April-Mayarticle by E-W, p113
- The Maha Bodhi, Vol. XXX, No. 7 July 1922
- The Maha Bodhi, Vol. 44 No. 2, February 1936article by E-W p49
- The Maha Bodhi, Vol. 62, No. 8, August 1954
Separated Materials
The Following books were in the Evans-Wentz Collection and have been distributed in the following manner:
Coleridge, E.P. The Plays of Euripides Vol. II Gifts & Exchange De Los Reyes, Isabelo, La Religion Antigua de los Filipinos Rare Book Collection Mirrielees, Edith Ronald, Fifty Years of Phi Beta Kappa at Stanford 1891-1941 G&E The Universal Self Instructor, Thomas Kelly, Publisher Rare Book Collection
The following periodicals have been given to the Libraries Serials Department:
The Canadian Theosophist Vol. XXIII, No. 10 Hamilton, December 15, 1942
The Canadian Theosophist Vol. XXIII, No. 11 Hamilton, January 15, 1943
The Maha Bodhi April Vol. 58 May Nos. 4-5
The Maha Bodhi Vol. 60 February No. 2